At the dawn of punk, there is no band
trashier than The Cramps.
>> [music]
>> The band's new lost album, Gravest Hits
Gravy, shows just how deep that garbage
goes. In October of 1977, a fresh freaky
Cramps drove to Ardent Studios to mix
some recordings with Alex Chilton. Some
of those recordings ended up on early
singles, and the rest, unknown to even
the most hardcore fans, ended up in
storage. That is, until Henry Rollins
and Ian MacKaye, punk legends but also
punk historians, got their hands on some
reel-to-reel tapes. The Cramps sound was
revved-up rockabilly that will scare the
squares, like on this early version of
TV Set.
>> [music]
>> But you also get this fuzzy tremolo
warped take on Paul Revere and the
Raiders that will fry your brain.
Cramps were often accused of kitsch, but
like the filmmakers Peppy Herman and
John Waters, The Cramps understood that
monster movies, leather jackets, and
early rock and roll are primal
distillation of American culture. So
many of these lost albums can feel like
dumpster dives, but in this case,
Gravest Hits Gravy is gold.